Guide to the Thomas W. Streeter Collection of Texas Manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Thomas W. Streeter collection of Texas manuscripts
1787-1864
WA MSS S-498-500
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4
(8 boxes)
The collection consists of letters, land claims, court papers, financial documents, public documents, narrative descriptions, and histories, recording the early history and development of Texas, including the conflicts between Texan and Mexican officials that culminated in the Texas Revolution. Each part is arranged alphabetically by the author, item title, or subject. Accompanied by Streeter's catalogue of his collection in two notebooks.
Streeter, Thomas W. (Thomas Winthrop), 1883-1965
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was purchased by Yale University Library from Thomas W. Streeter.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Thomas W. Streeter Collection of Texas Manuscripts is divided into three sections: I. Personal Files, 1787-1882 (WA MSS S-498); II. Signers of the Texas Declaration of Independence, 1820-1852 (WA MSS S-499); and III. Texas Subjects, 1818-1864 (WA MSS S-500). The collection consists of autographs, letters, land claims, court papers, financial documents, public documents, narratives and histories, recording the history and development of Texas. Each section is arranged alphabetically by the author, item title, or subject.
Section I, Personal Files, contains a wide range of documents including much correspondence between important figures in the early history of Texas, the movement to declare independence from Mexico, and the military conflict between Texas rebels and Mexican officials. Principal correspondents in this collection include Stephen F. Austin, Moses Austin Bryan, Henry Smith, James Kerr, Ramón Músquiz, Mier y Teran, Ira Randolph Lewis, and Thomas Jefferson Chambers.
Section II, Signers of the Texas Declaration of Independence is essentially a collection of miscellaneous papers that document the autographs of 37 signatures to the Texas Declaration of Independence. Section III, Texas Subjects, consists of files arranged around places, institutions and episodes of early Texas history.
The Appendix, Streeter's "Catalogue of Texas Manuscripts," contains two notebooks in which Thomas Streeter recorded the description and provenance of each item in the above collections. The catalogues are divided into the same three sections as listed above, each section arranged alphabetically. Some items listed in the notebooks have been cataloged separately (e.g. the Thomas Falconer diary and account).
Autographs -- Texas; Business -- Texas; Champ d'Asile (Tex.); Indians of North America -- Texas; Land grants -- Texas; Real property -- Texas; Texan Santa Fé Expedition, 1841; Coahuila and Texas (Mexico) -- History; Matagorda (Tex.); Mexico -- Foreign relations -- Texas; Texas -- Emigration and immigration; Texas -- Foreign relations -- Mexico; Texas -- History -- 1846-1950; Texas -- History -- Republic, 1836-1846; Texas -- History -- Revolution, 1835-1836; Texas -- History -- To 1846; Texas -- Politics and government; Public officers -- Texas; Arnold, William, -1833; Austin, Moses, 1761-1821; Austin, Stephen F. (Stephen Fuller), 1793-1836; Borden, Gail, 1801-1874; Bowie, Jim, 1796?-1836; Bryan, Moses Austin, 1817-1895; Chambers, Thomas Jefferson, 1802-1865; Crockett, Davy, 1786-1836; Donelson, Andrew Jackson, 1799-1871; Fisher, George, 1795-1873; Fisher, Samuel Rhoads, 1794-1839; Holley, Mary Austin, 1784-1846; Houston, Sam, 1793-1863; Huston, Felix, 1800-1857; Kerr, James, 1790-1850; Lamar, Mirabeau B. (Mirabeau Buonaparte), 1798-1859; Lewis, Ira Randolph, 1800-1867; Mier y Teran, Manuel de; Músquiz, Ramón, approximately 1797-; Nolan, Philip, 1771-1801; Smith, Henry, 1788-1851; Somervell, Alexander, 1796-1854; Streeter, Thomas W. (Thomas Winthrop), 1883-1965; Travis, William Barret, 1809-1836; Chihuahua Navigation Company; Texas ( Declaration of Independence Signers)
- Personal Files, 1787-1882, WA MSS S-498
  - Abbott, Lancelot
    - ALS to Henry Smith, New Orleans, 1838 Mar 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      2 p. 29 cm.
      Relates to counterfeit Texas money
      and the Lotteries.
  - Adams, Warren, defendant
    - Copy of Bill of indictment against Warren Adams and Asa Smith for the murder of Noah Scott, Austin, 1841 Apr (Box 1, Folder 2)
      3 p. 32 cm.
      Signed: Henry P. Brewster,
      District Atty.
  - Alaman, Lucas, 1792-1853
    - LS to Stephen F. Austin, Mejico, 1832 Apr 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      2 p. 25 cm.
      Concerns rumors of a revolutionary
      movement in Texas.
      Enclosed photostat.
  - Almonte, Juan Nepomuceno, 1803-1869
    - Copy of letter to the Ministerio de lo Interior, Mexico City, 1841 Aug 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Accompanied by a typed translation.
      Concerns the land contract of
      Baron Racknitz.
  - Andrews, Edmund
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Brazoria, Tex, 1840 Jun 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      1 p. 28 cm.
      About land for sale in Brazoria.
  - Anthony, D. W., d.1833
    - Sworn deposition, Brazoria, 1833 Jun 26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      1 p. 25 cm.
      Concerning his newspaper, The
      Constitutional Advocate and Texas
      Public Advertiser.
  - Aquilira, Ignacio
    - Translation of Ignacio Aquilira claim for 11 leagues of land on Trinity River. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      16 p. 32 cm.
      Title from docket.
  - Arista, Marian, Pres. Mexico, 1802-1855
    - Copy of letter to the Ministro de la Guerra, General Headquarters at Lampasos, 1841 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      4 p. 31.5 cm.
      At end: Son copias Mexico 10 de
      1841 Juan L. Velazquez de Leon.
      Accompanied by a typed
      translation and list of documents.
      Encloses letter of Baron von
      Racknitz, concerned with his
      intentions to colonize near the
      Nueces River.
  - Arnold, William
    - Receipts, letters, memoranda, accounts, deeds, documents, commissions, and agreements, 1813-33 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      51 p. 20-44 cm.
  - Aury, Louis-Michel
    - 2 ALS to Bernardo Gutierez [de Lara], Bahia de Galveston, 1816 Oct 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      3 p. 24-31 cm.
      One letter in Spanish and one in
      French.
      Concerned with Herrera's attempt to
      set up a revolutionary government
      in Mexico.
      Enclosed typed transcriptions.
  - Austin, Moses, 1761-1821
    - ALS to George Wescott, Richmond., 1787 Jun 28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      2 p. 20 cm.
      Enclosed silhouette of Austin.
    - Signed draft on Andrew Scott, Mine a Burton, Mo, 1812 Nov 26 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      1 p. 16 cm.
  - Austin, Stephen Fuller, 1793-1836
    - D.S. to David Harris, San Felipe de Austin, 1824 Aug 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      3 p. 31 cm.
      Attested by: Samuel M. Williams,
      Baron de Bastrop, John Austin.
      Stamp tax receipt on p. 1 signed
      Sylvenus Castleman.
      Grants one sitio of land on the
      west side of the San Jacinto
      River.
      Enclosed two engraved portraits
      of Austin.
    - Signed agreement with William C. White, San Felipe de Austin, 1828 Mar 16 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      1 p. 31.5 cm.
      Relates to a league and a half of
      land on Oyster Creek.
    - Signed memorandum, San Felipe de Austin, 1829 Feb 18 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      1 p. 24 cm.
      List of settlers from New York.
    - Petition to the Governor of the state of Coahuila and Texas, Villa de Austin, 1830 Jun 14 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Accompanied by typed translation.
      Requesting 11 sitios of land.
    - AL to General Teran, Bexar, 1832 Mar 21 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      3 p. 25 cm.
      Requesting that Texas become a
      state of the Mexican Federation
      and discussing current political
      affairs.
    - Draft of letter to Manuel de Mier y Teran, Matamoras, 1832 Jun 17 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      4 p. 25 cm.
      Discusses his opposition to
      sending military forces to Texas.
    - LS to Ramon Musquiz, Matamoras, 1832 Jun 26 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      3 p. 23 cm.
      Tear interferes with text.
      Concerns disturbances in Anahuac.
    - Draft of letter to Manuel Mier y Teran, n.p, 1832 Jun 27 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Discusses the political situation
      in Texas.
    - ALS to Ayuntamiento of Brazoria, Matamoros, 1833 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      4 p. 32 cm.
      Austin pledges that the people of
      Texas will uphold the revenue laws,
      so there is no need of a large
      military force.
    - ALS to Carlos Garcia, Mexico City, 1833 Aug 2 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      1 p. 27 cm.
      Speaks of critical situation of
      Texas and asks that it be recog-
      nized as a state of the Mexican
      Federation.
    - Signed note to E.W. Gregory, Mexico, 1833 Oct 23 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      1 p. 25.5 cm.
      Tear interferes with some text.
    - Draft on E.W. Gregory, Mexico, 1833 Oct 23 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      One draft in favor of Francisco
      Martinez and one in favor of
      Evaristo Gonzalez.
    - Copy of letter to "Dear Brother", Prison of Arcardo, 1834 Aug 25 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      8 p. 32.5 cm.
      Last paragraph dated Aug 26.
      Describes the political situation
      and his imprisonment.
    - ALS to F.W. Johnson and others, Quintana, Texas, 1835 Dec 22 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      4 p. 28 cm.
      Addressed to F.W. Johnson, Daniel
      Parker, D.C. Burnet, J.W. Robin-
      son, Wyatt Hanks, P. Soublett,
      Asa Hoxy.
      Criticizes the idea of a standing
      army for Texas.
    - ALS to G.C. Childress, W.H. Wharton, and Robert Hamilton, New Orleans, 1836 Jun 11 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      3 p. 28 cm.
      With typescript.
      On Texan independence.
    - ALS to "Gentlemen", New Orleans, 1836 Jun 14 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Concerns Texas' independence and
      her future.
    - ALS to the Chairman of the Joint Committee, Dept. of State, Columbia, [Texas], 1836 Dec 19 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Alleged to be the last letter
      penned by Austin. Includes letter
      from Alex Dienst (donor) concerning
      provenance of the letter.
  - Baine, Moses
    - Title bond to L.L. Veeder, San Felipe de Austin, Texas, 1831 Nov 3 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Signed: Moses Baine, Walter
      White, and two witnesses.
      At end: The foregoing is a substan-
      tial translation of the original
      document on file in the archives of
      the Alcalde of Austin. San Felipe
      de Austin, December 27, 1833. W.
      Barret Travis.
  - Barbey, Theodore
    - ALS to F.J. Cuttner, New York, 1845 Jul 11 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      3 p. with address, 21 cm.
  - Beers, St. John & Co.
    - Signed draft for one thousand dollars payable to Stephen F. Austin per E.W. Gregory, New Orleans, 1833 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Endorsed by S.F. Austin on p. 3
      to Mario Garcia de Tejada and
      Francisco Pizarro Martinez.
  - Bell, Peter Hansborough, 1810-1898
    - ALS to Felix Huston, City of Austin, 1841 Jan 30 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      On army affairs and a bill to
      disband the regular Army.
  - Borden, Gail, 1801-1874
    - ALS to Henry Smith, Port of Galveston, 1838 Mar 27 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      3 p. 24.5 cm.
      Concerning excessive spending of
      money by the navy.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Galveston, 1839 Dec 28 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      2 p. 31.5 cm.
      Concerning the administration of
      the estate of Mrs. Jaques.
    - An unsigned incomplete draft of a letter, n.p., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
      3 p. 41 cm.
      Concerned with Borden's work on
      the preservation of milk.
  - Borden, John Petit, 1812-1890
    - ALS to Moses Austin Bryan, Egypt, Texas, 1837 Aug 7 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      Tells of his appointment as land
      commissioner and of the practical
      disbanding of the army.
  - Borden, Thomas Henry, 1804-1877
    - Signed agreement, San Felipe de Austin, 1833 Nov 20 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      1 p. 32.5 cm.
      Signed: Thomas H. Borden, and Ira
      R. Lewis.
      Agreement to rent and lease his
      house to Ira Lewis.
  - Bowie, James, 1805-1836
    - LS to "Comand.te. del Ejercito de Tejas", Fortaleza del Alamo, 1836 Feb 23 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Accompanied by typed translation
      and two negative photostats.
      Discusses a truce.
  - Brush, John S. (defendant)
    - Bail bond for John S. Brush accused of the murder of Seaborn Jones, San Felipe de Austin, 1832 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      2 p. 31 cm.
      Signed: John S. Brush, Ira R.
      Lewis, Horatio Chriesman and
      six others.
  - Bullock, James Whitis, b.1788?
    - ALS to "The Alcalde of San Felipe de Austin," Nacogdoches, 1832 Aug 9 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      An account of the surrender of
      Col. Piedras.
  - Burnet, David Gouverneur, 1788-1870
    - ALS to Felix Houston [sic], Oakland, Texas, 1842 Jan 18 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      Accompanied by typescript.
      Contains political news.
    - ALS to Lewis I. Cist, Esq., Oakland Texas, 1842 Dec 18 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      Printed obituary on p. 3.
      Discusses revolution in Texas.
  - Butler, Anthony, 1787-1849
    - 4 ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Houston, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      10 p. 25 cm.
      Letters dated 1839 Jan 25, Feb 10,
      Apr 20, May 2.
      Discusses current Texas political
      issues.
  - Calhoun, John Caldwell, 1782-1850
    - Signed copy of a letter to A. Upshur, Fort Hill, 1843 Aug 27 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      Discusses British intentions in
      Texas.
  - Canfield, Alanson Wyllys, d.1864
    - Certificate of printer in application of John R. Clute for discharge in bankruptcy, San Augustine, Texas, 1842 Mar 10 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      1 p. 20 cm.
      Signed: A.W. Canfield.
  - Chambers, Thomas Jefferson, 1802-1865
    - Signed memorandum to I.R. Lewis, n.p., 1833 Aug 22 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      Signed note at bottom to A. Fiske
      & Co. dated San Felipe de Austin,
      August 22, 1833.
    - ALS to James Kerr, La Bahia, Texas, 1829 Dec 7 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      Attached are instructions in
      Spanish signed: J. Antonio Padilla
      and Thomas Jefferson Chambers.
      Appoints Kerr Surveyor and asks
      that he survey three sitios of land
      acquired by P.F. Dimitt.
    - Signed document, San Felipe de Austin, Texas, 1833 Aug 17 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      2 p. 33 cm.
      Transferring power of attorney to
      administer land owned by Chambers
      and Juan Antonio Padilla to I.R.
      Lewis.
    - ADS to "The Judge in the 1st Instance of the municipality of Austin," San Felipe de Austin, 1834 Nov 1 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      2 p. 26.5 cm.
      Sworn before: David G. Burnet.
      An appeal of the decision in the
      York vs. Chambers case.
    - ALS to Col. Ira R. Lewis, Nashville, Tenn, 1836 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      1 p. 24.5 cm.
    - ALS to Mrs. Eliza Lewis, Houston, Texas, 1839 Jun 7 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Signed document, Independence, Texas, 1847 Feb 24 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      1 p. 31 cm.
      On verso, signed notarization:
      Moses Park.
      Ira R. Lewis.
  - Coahuila and Texas (State). Gobernador
    - 1824-1826 (Rafael Gonzales)
      - Copy of message to Congress concerning courts, Saltillo, 1826 Dec 21 (Box 1, Folder 54)
        4 p. 31 cm.
        Endorsed: Opinion del Gob. del Es-
        tado sobre tribunales de justicia.
        Enclosed translation.
    - 1827-1831 (Jose Maria Viesca)
      - LS to El Senor Ministerio de Estado y de relaciones, Leona Viacario, 1828 Aug 18 (Box 1, Folder 55)
        3 p. 30 cm.
        Signed: J.M. Viesca and J. Antonio
        Padilla.
        Forwarding petition of John Cameron
        for the land of Col. Reuben Ross.
      - LS to Stephen F. Austin, Leona Vicario, 1831 Feb 28 (Box 1, Folder 56)
        2 p. 20.5 cm.
        Signed: Viesca and Santiago del Valle.
        With photostat.
        Acknowledges receipt of Austin's
        letter of 18 Feb.
    - 1831-1832 (Letona)
      - LS to Stephen F. Austin, Leona Vicario, 1832 Jan 9 (Box 1, Folder 57)
        3 p. 30.5 cm.
        Signed: Santiago del Valle.
        Notification of substitutes to
        the Congress.
      - LS to Stephen F. Austin, Leona Vicario, 1832 Apr 11 (Box 1, Folder 58)
        3 p. 20.5 cm.
        Signed by Santiago del Valle.
        Concerns land distribution in
    - 1835 (Eca y Musquiz, Rafael)
      - LS to El Juez Superior de Tejas, Leona Vicario, 1835 Aug 21 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Coahuila and Texas (State). Laws, statutes, etc.
    - Translation of Decree number 39 regulating the administration of justice, Saltillo, 1827 Jun 22 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      24 p. 30 cm.
      Signed: Juan Antonio Padilla.
    - Translation of two laws pertaining to Colonization, Saltillo, 1830 Apr 7 (Box 1, Folder 61)
      Second document n.p., 1828 May 16.
    - Translation of two laws pertaining to Colonization, n.p, 1835 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 62)
      Second document n.p., 1835 May 18.
  - Coahuila and Texas (State). Secretario
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Leona Vicario, 1832 Sep 15 (Box 1, Folder 63)
      Concerned with the current
      political situation.
      Enclosed typed translation.
  - Cooke, Louis P., 1811-1849
    - Receipt for land deed from I.R. Lewis, Nacogdoches, 1843 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Collinsworth, George Morse, b.1810
    - ALS to "Mr. or Mrs. Lynn," Goliad, Texas, 1835 Oct 10 (Box 1, Folder 65)
      Asking that the message to Maj.
      Smith be forwarded with all speed.
    - ALS to Capt. B.F. Smith, Goliad, Texas, 1835 Oct 10 (Box 1, Folder 66)
      Tells of capture of the fort and
      possible uprising of the citizens.
    - ALS to Capt. Benj. F. Smith, Goliad, Texas, 1835 Oct 10 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Crockett, David, 1788-1836
    - ALS to John W. Crockett, Washington City, 1834 Jan 10 (Box 1, Folder 68)
      3 p. 25.5 cm.
      Discusses plans for his
      autobiography and the current
  - Dallam, James Wilmer, 1818-1847
    - Memorandum to Col. Lewis, n.p. (Box 2, Folder 69)
      List of bonds.
  - Decrow, Thomas
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, n.p, 1839 Apr 6 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      1 p. 19.5 cm.
      Asks for legal advice concerning
      his slave.
  - Demorse, Charles, 1816-1887
    - 7 ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Austin and Clarksville, 1841-48 (Box 2, Folder 71)
      Dated 1841 Jul 24 - 1848 Oct 17.
      17 p. 26-26.5 cm.
      Concerning business and legal
      matters.
  - Dewitt, Green, 1787-1835
    - Petition for land grant to the governor of the State of Coahuila and Texas, Saltillo, 1825 Apr 15 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      4 p. 33 cm.
      Copy dated 1825 Jul 11, San Felipe
      de Austin signed: Rafael Gonzalez,
      George Dewitt, Juan Antonio
      Padilla, Samuel M. Williams.
    - Signed document, La Baca Dewitt's Colony, 1827 Jul 14 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      1 p. 30.5 cm.
      Endorsed on verso.
      Appointing James Kerr his agent and
      giving him power of attorney.
    - Signed agreement with James Kerr, Gonzales, Texas, 1829 Jan 17 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      Signed: James Kerr
  - Dickson, David H.
    - ALS to Gen. Huston, Columbia, Texas, 1836 Nov 4 (Box 2, Folder 74A)
      Asks that Huston write a recom-
      mendation so he can obtain a
      commission.
  - Dimitt, Philip F.
    - ALS to Gen. F. Huston, Dimitts Point, Texas, 1837 Jan 28 (Box 2, Folder 75)
      Requests that the sale of whiskey
      to soldiers be stopped.
    - ALS to "The Honorable Committee," Dimitt's Point, Texas, 1838 Feb 28 (Box 2, Folder 76)
      2 p. 32.5 cm.
      "A true copy from the original"
      signed: P. Dimitt.
      Reports of a scouting trip.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, St. Antonio Rio? (Box 2, Folder 77)
      Concerns the Mexican Federalists
      revolt and the opportunity of
      deriving profits for Texas from it.
  - Dinsmore, Silas, d.1846
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, Velasco, 1834 May 31 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      Concerns the trade of a house
      and lot.
    - ALS to D.D.D. Bakes, Velasco, 1834 Jun 14 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Contract of transfer of land to I.R. Lewis, Matagorda, 1834 Sep 8 (Box 2, Folder 80)
      1 p. 33 cm.
      Signed: Silas Dinsmore and I.R.
  - Donaker, Isaac
    - Agreement as to terms of duel between I.R. Lewis and W.H. Jack, San Felipe de Austin, 1832 Aug 4 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      2 p. 32 cm.
      Signed: Isaac Donaker, T. McQueen,
      Thomas F. McKinney, F.W. Johnson.
  - Donelson, Andrew Jackson, 1799-1871
    - ALS to Charles A. Wickliffe, "Near Washington", Texas, 1845 Jun 7 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      Concerns proclamation of the
      president suspending hostilities
      between Texas and Mexico until
      annexation is decided on by Texas.
      Enclosed envelope and clippings.
    - ALS to A.O.P. Nicholson, Washington, Texas, 1845 Jun 23 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      Concerns a proposed treaty between
      Mexico and Texas.
    - ALS to Charles A. Wickliffe, Washington, Texas, 1845 Jul 1 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      Concerns the constitutional conven-
      tion, General Taylor's troops and
      other current topics.
    - ALS to Charles A. Wickliffe, Galveston, 1845 Jul 29 (Box 2, Folder 85)
      Speaks of current affairs in
      Galveston.
  - Duffau, Francis T.
    - ALS to Francisco Pizarro Martinez, Warrenton, Miss., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 86)
      Offers his services to the Mexican
      government.
  - Duke, Thomas Marshall, 1795-1867
    - ALS to "Dear Col." [Ira R. Lewis?], Port Calhoun, 1841 Sep 29 (Box 2, Folder 87)
      Asks to borrow Mr. Lewis' pistols.
  - Durst, John
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, Mount Sterling, 1838 Oct 24 (Box 2, Folder 88)
      7 p. 24 cm.
      Accompanied by a typescript.
      Gives a detailed account of a
      battle with the Kickapoo Indians.
  - Dwyer, Edward
    - ALS to Gen. Felix Huston, Labaca, 1836 Oct 28 (Box 2, Folder 89)
      On behalf of Manuel Zepeda request-
      ing permission for him to carry
      his cattle to Bexar.
  - Dyer, Leon
    - ALS to Gen. Felix Huston, Columbia, 1836 Oct 26 (Box 2, Folder 90)
      Tells of army affairs.
  - Edwards, Haden, 1771-1849
    - Copy of petition for empresario land grant in Texas, Mexico, 1823 Aug 22 (Box 2, Folder 91)
      Incomplete.
  - Estados internas de oriente. Com. Gen. 1834-35 (Cos)
    - Full heading: Comandante General, 1834-1835 (Cos)
      - Translation of proclamation to Texans, Matamoras, 1835 Jul 12 (Box 2, Folder 92)
        Asks that Texans regard troops as
        sent there for their protection
        and not to heed agitators.
  - Fannin, James Walker, 1804-1836
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Matagorda, 1835 Dec 13 (Box 2, Folder 93)
      Offering to buy land in Matagorda.
    - ALS to Saml. A. White, Fort Defiance, Goliad, 1836 Mar 9 (Box 2, Folder 94)
      About collecting and protecting
      supplies.
  - Field, Joseph E.
    - Land contract between Joseph Field and E.R. Wightman, n.p, 1837 Jan 2 (Box 2, Folder 95)
      Map on p. 4.
      Signed by three witnesses.
  - Filisola, Vicente, 1785-1850
    - LS to Don Jose Ma Michelena, Toluca, 1845 Mar 23 (Box 2, Folder 96)
      2 p. 27.5 cm.
      Asks for all the pickets belonging
      to the 6th and Morelia Cavalry.
  - Fisher, George, 1795-1873
    - 5 ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Houston and Austin. (Box 2, Folder 97)
      Dated 1838 Oct 18, Dec 18
      1847 Mar 1, Mar 31, Jun 6.
      12 p. 25.5 cm.
      Concerning a draft drawn on Seth
      Ingram, business, and requesting
      legal advice.
  - Fisher, Samuel Rhoads, 1794-1839
    - ALS to Redwood Fisher, Matagorda, 1836 Feb 9 (Box 2, Folder 98)
      2 p. with address, 25 cm.
      Note signed by Thomas Jefferson
      Chambers is appended.
      Introduction of Chambers.
    - 8 ALS to Ira R. Lewis, v.p., 1835-39 (Box 2, Folder 99)
      1835 May 5 - 1839 Jan 10
      11 p. 24.5-31.5 cm.
      Concerns political affairs.
  - Fisher, William, S.
    - ALS to Gen. Pedro de Ampudia, Mier, 1842 Dec 26 (Box 2, Folder 100)